I did use you.
我确实利用了你。
But when I saw you,
但当我看到你的时候
to see you.
为了见你。
What about you?
你呢？
Are you happy?
你快乐吗？
I knew it.
我就知道。
I don't want you to be involved.
我不想让你参与其中。
I want you to leave safely.
我希望你能安全离开。
Why do you still want to marry me?
为什么你还想嫁给我？
You won't go?
你不去吗？
I think
我认为
I'll fulfill my promise to you.
我会履行对你的承诺。
Really?
真的吗？
But if I marry you,
但如果我嫁给你
It's just to kill Yamashita.
就是为了杀掉山下。
Will you believe it?
你会相信吗？
He would.
他会。
No matter what.
无论。
Do you think I love you?
你认为我爱你吗？
Certainly.
当然。
You should be confident of yourself.
你应该对自己有信心。
Look how proud you are.
看看你有多骄傲。
You're really something.
你真是个东西。
I thought you were killed by Officer Uchida.
我以为你是被内田警官杀的
I was trying to save myself.
我试图拯救自己。
I told Ueda that
我告诉上田
as long as I follow Wang Dapu,
只要我跟着王大璞，
we might have a chance to get the copper plate.
我们也许有机会得到铜板。
Uchida trusts you.
内田相信你。
Right.
正确的。
He trusts me more than you do.
他比你更信任我。
Is he mad at me?
他生我的气吗？
The Japanese gave the order.
日本人下了命令。
If I don't hand you over to the Imperial Prison, OK?
如果我不把你交给皇狱，可以吗？
That's right, Jiaping.
没错，嘉平。
Look at yourself.
看看你自己。
You were put in the detention center.
你被关进了看守所。
But the Japanese never tortured you.
但日本人从来没有折磨过你。
They are all people, Manager Luo.
都是人啊，洛经理。
To help you
来帮你
to plead for you.
为你求情。
Look at this.
看这个。
Shuangtao defended me.
Shuangtao defended me.
Thank you.
谢谢。
Look at this.
看这个。
All right.
好的。
I know you are wronged.
我知道你受委屈了。
I will
我会
I'll hold a banquet for you
我会为你举办宴会
get rid of the old to make way for the new
革故鼎新
by the way, Luo,
顺便说一下，罗
how is the business recently?
最近生意怎么样？
Still the same.
还是一样。
Without Zhao An,
没有赵安，
this is much quieter.
这安静多了。
That's strange.
真奇怪。
Zhao An has so many lives.
赵安有这么多条命。
How can he be the five of hearts?
他怎么可能是红心五呢？
How many lives
多少条生命
of Wang Tianmu's hands?
王天木的手？
We've already pledged our allegiance here.
我们已经在这里宣誓效忠了。
That's right.
这是正确的。
Now,
现在，
zhao An has finally pulled out the candle.
赵安终于拔出了蜡烛。
From now on, Taihe Trading Firm
从此，泰和商行
will be controlled by us.
将由我们控制。
Do you remember Xiucai Qian who guarded the door?
你还记得看门的钱秀才吗？
Even he
就连他
want to seek help from me.
想向我寻求帮助。
And work for me.
并为我工作。
Many people nowadays
现在很多人
they should know about themselves.
他们应该了解自己。
Qian Xiucai,
Qian Xiucai,
by the way,
顺便一提，
copper coins of the Communist Party of China
中国共产党铜币
the copper coins?
铜币？
I didn't only see
我不仅看到了
at the same time.
同时。
The Japanese have been dying for this.
日本人为此已经死了。
A combination of military damage and economic damage.
军事损失和经济损失的结合。
It seems that the Japanese executives
看来日本高管
has changed their thinking.
改变了他们的想法。
What a pity!
真可惜！
If I can get this bronze plate,
如果我能得到这块铜牌
let alone this is your car,
更不用说这是你的车，
I didn't even bother to sit in Naoki Uchida's car.
我什至懒得坐内田直树的车。
You only talk big things.
你只讲大事。
Think about our future.
想想我们的未来。
Now Japan and the United States are going to war.
现在日本和美国要开战了。
I'm afraid it's inevitable.
恐怕这是不可避免的。
The situation
情况
the situation in the future.
未来的情况。
Come on.
快点。
Shuangtao.
Shuangtao.
Go back and have a rest
回去休息吧
I have a few more words with Jiaping.
我跟家平还有几句话。
Newspaper. Newspaper.
报纸。报纸。
What's the matter?
怎么了？
I know you are wronged.
我知道你受委屈了。
Have a good rest.
好好休息。
Don't go to work in a hurry.
不要着急去上班。
There's another thing.
还有一件事。
I made a deal recently.
我最近做了一笔交易。
I have to find someone I'm trustworthy.
我必须找到一个我可以信赖的人。
Someone you trust.
你信任的人。
Well, there?
嗯，在那里？
The big spoon doesn't work well.
大勺子不好用。
I still need you the most.
我还是最需要你。
What deal?
什么交易？
I'll tell you when.
我会告诉你什么时候。
But you have to remember
但你必须记住
what I told you in the car.
我在车里告诉你的
The Japanese are unreliable now.
日本人现在已经不靠谱了。
We have to think about our own future.
我们必须考虑我们自己的未来。
You're making it sound unclear.
你说得听起来不清楚。
But I'm telling you that
但我告诉你
don't think I'll forgive you.
别以为我会原谅你。
Have a good rest.
好好休息。
I can understand now.
我现在能明白了。
To protect your identity,
为了保护您的身份，
you secretly helped me.
你暗中帮助了我。
I thought they got information
我以为他们得到了信息
we got the information from you.
我们从你那里得到了信息。
For example, the time you saved people in Hongyun Hotel.
比如你在红运宾馆救人的那次。
Were leaked to me on purpose.
是故意泄露给我的。
You have helped me before.
你以前帮助过我。
Just like the time that you killed Feng Qi.
就像你杀了风起那次一样。
Without your evidence,
没有你的证据，
I wouldn't have
我不会有
just confirm Feng Qi's crime.
只是确认了冯琪的犯罪行为。
Do you think
你认为
are we different bedfellows?
我们是不同的同床异梦吗？
It is.
这是。
But that doesn't count
但这不算
even the dream of our couple
甚至是我们夫妇的梦想
will eventually come together.
最终会走到一起。
So you brought back
所以你带回来了
some files about the CPC
一些关于CPC的文件
he wanted me to see
他想让我看到
Including the files of Lu.
包括陆的档案。
Gave a lot of thought to this.
对此，思考了很多。
Back then, I made up my mind
那时我就​​下定决心
to win you over.
来赢得你的支持。
But I can't be honest with you.
但我不能对你说实话。
So I can only
所以我只能
In a subtle way.
以一种微妙的方式。
I have to say that
我不得不说
you've been very helpful
你很有帮助
the ideological work.
思想工作。
Because I know you.
因为我认识你。
I know you.
我认识你。
What kind of person you want to be.
你想成为什么样的人。
Think about
想一想
the one where our respective missions
我们各自的使命所在
Is that Ci'an Hospital?
是慈安医院吗？
You must have been following the clue to the magpie.
你一定是在追踪喜鹊的线索。
That's why you appeared there.
这就是你出现在那里的原因。
That's right.
这是正确的。
We're investigating
我们正在调查
the formula of the paper used for the coin currency stolen by Juntong spies
军统特务窃取的钱币所用纸张的配方
and the copper plate.
和铜板。
Now thinking back,
现在回想起来，
you are really good at acting.
你真的很擅长表演。
She knew about my identity,
她知道我的身份，
but pretended to be scared.
但假装很害怕。
If a man can act,
一个人如果会行动，
he must be forced by your women.
他一定是被你的女人强迫的。
And confess yourself like this?
还这样表白自己？
Come on.
快点。
How many other dramas and lies
还有多少戏剧和谎言
and how many lies you told me.
以及你对我说了多少谎言。
I swear.
我发誓。
Aside from my identity,
除了我的身份之外，
about my identity.
关于我的身份。
I don't believe that.
我不相信。
When a man lies,
当一个人说谎的时候，
It's only the first and countless times.
这只是第一次，还有无数次。
You've lied to me before.
你以前骗过我。
That's different.
那不一样。
Women lie
Women lie
so that men won't be sad.
这样男人就不会悲伤。
When a man lies,
当一个人说谎的时候，
Is purely to lie to women.
纯粹是为了骗女人。
What kind of nonsense are you talking about?
你在说什么废话？
You intentionally exposed yourself that day,
那天你故意暴露自己，
so you could join us
这样你就可以加入我们
to raid the counterfeit factory with us?
和我们一起突袭假冒工厂？
I only saw that there is so much evidence
我只看到有这么多证据
and you didn't have a reason to think so
你没有理由这么想
and became anxious.
并变得焦虑。
Of course,
当然，
the most important thing is your safety.
最重要的是您的安全。
The last sentence
最后一句话
really touches me.
真的很触动我。
Did you start to suspect me
你有没有开始怀疑我
after that operation?
那次手术之后？
I should've doubted you,
我早该怀疑你的
but I didn't expect that
但我没想到
that Zhao An replaced it.
赵安取代了它。
It was a nice design.
这是一个很好的设计。
What do you mean by that?
你是什​​么意思？
Did you think
你觉得
that I should be inferior to you?
难道我就应该不如你吗？
I didn't say that.
我没那么说。
Otherwise, I won't let you know more
不然我不会让你知道更多
the Communist Party's anti-Japanese actions
共产党的抗日行动
and the communist ideology.
和共产主义意识形态。
I don't know either
我也不知道
I know you well enough.
我很了解你。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
It's enough for you to know me
你认识我就足够了
knowing me
认识我
and you know us.
你了解我们。
I have now completely broken
我现在已经彻底崩溃了
with Juntong.
与俊通。
Would you accept an ex-military unification member?
你会接受前军统成员吗？
I'll testify for you!
我来为你作证！
You're not like Jiang Zhaoguo and the others.
你不像蒋兆国他们。
You always insisted
你一直坚持
our call for unity
我们呼吁团结
that we have called for.
这是我们所呼吁的。
Your thoughts and actions
你的想法和行动
In thought and action.
在思想和行动上。
I'm ready.
我准备好了。
Alright.
好吧。
I'll report to the organization as soon as possible
我会尽快向组织汇报
so that one day,
所以有一天，
that we can all
我们都可以
as soon as possible.
尽快地。
I'm looking forward to that day to come.
我期待着那一天的到来。
Alright.
好吧。
But we need to be more careful
但我们需要更加小心
while waiting.
在等待的同时。
After all, you've taken away the copper plate from Jiang Zhaoguo.
毕竟，你已经把蒋兆国的铜板拿走了。
He must be
他肯定是
he must be so exasperated that
他一定很生气
assassination.
暗杀。
That's what he did.
他就是这么做的。
I know how they are.
我知道他们怎么样。
They can't handle me.
他们对付不了我。
Now we have the copper plate.
现在我们有了铜板。
When we find the paper formula of the coin,
当我们找到硬币的纸面公式时，
the real counterfeit factory
真正的假冒工厂
my mission is over.
我的任务结束了。
I've got to finish
我必须完成
with you.
与你。
Four of clubs,
四家具乐部，
five of hearts.
五颗心。
We're officially together.
我们正式在一起了
Pay more attention to your safety.
更加注意您的安全。
As for the business,
至于业务方面，
let's not go there.
我们不要去那里。
I'll talk to Luo Guanqun
我去跟罗冠群谈谈
tell her that my wife worked so hard for me
告诉她我的妻子为我付出了很多努力
and she's resting at home.
她正在家里休息。
You should stay at home.
你应该呆在家里。
I won't go anywhere.
我哪儿也不去。
Come on.
快点。
What about you?
你呢？
I have to...
我必须...
I need to contact my superior.
我需要联系我的上级。
Who is your superior?
谁是你的上级？
How do you usually contact?
平时怎么联系？
My superior is...
我的上级是...
My superior is the Communist Party of China.
我的上级是中国共产党。
The way we communicate with each other
我们彼此沟通的方式
that's a communist ideology.
这是共产主义意识形态。
That means he didn't say anything.
这意味着他什么也没说。
He still doesn't treat me as one of his own.
他仍然没有把我当作他的一员。
The copper coin has been recovered.
铜币已被追回。
Please indicate when and where to exchange the coins.
请注明兑换硬币的时间和地点。
In this operation,
在这次操作中，
In the operation.
在操作中。
She might not stay here for long.
她可能不会在这里呆太久。
Zuo Shuangtao has known my identity.
左双涛已经知道我的身份了。
She has broken with Juntong
她已经和俊桐决裂了
to join the underground organizations of our Party.
加入我们党的地下组织。
Please approve it.
请批准。
Come in.
进来。
Manager Luo,
Manager Luo,
there is a response.
有回应。
What about
关于什么
he agreed to our asking price.
他同意了我们的要价。
Next,
下一个，
one step at a time.
一步一步来。
Follow the plan.
遵循计划。
Yes
是的
nice to meet you, sir.
很高兴认识你，先生。
I've booked a cafe on the second floor.
我订了二楼的咖啡厅。
This way, please.
这边请。
902.
902.
The magpie is in 902.
喜鹊在902。
Hurry!
匆忙！
Yes
是的
mister.
先生。
This place is sealed off.
这个地方被封锁了。
Get out of here!
离开这里！
Let go of me!
让我走！
We've searched every body.
我们搜查了每一具尸体。
I didn't find anything.
我什么也没找到。
That's impossible.
这不可能。
I found something.
我发现了一些东西。
The formula of the coin paper
硬币纸的配方
Is on him.
就在他身上。
Who's that?
那是谁？
Who are you?
你是谁？
You don't want to tell me?
你不想告诉我吗？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
I don't know.
我不知道。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
What do you want?
你想要什么？
See that?
看到了吗？
Boss.
老板。
What to do with that magpie?
那只喜鹊该怎么办？
Not to be worth a hair
不值一毛钱
I suspect that the magpie
我怀疑是喜鹊
hid the formula in her wound.
把配方藏在她的伤口里。
So I opened it with a dagger.
于是我用匕首把它打开了。
But I didn't find it.
但我没有找到。
But I found a piece of brown paper.
但我发现了一张牛皮纸。
This proves my judgment is right.
这证明我的判断是正确的。
But maybe someone
但也许有人
maybe someone took it earlier
也许有人更早拿走了它
chief Chen
陈科长
sit down
坐下
second Blade.
第二把刀片。
Seeing me back,
看到我回来，
right?
正确的？
How would I dare to be disappointed?
我怎么敢失望呢？
I was so scared.
我很害怕。
No, I didn't mean that.
不，我不是这个意思。
We were surprised and happy
我们感到惊讶和高兴
you also saw the ending
你也看到了结局
and Chen Dugu.
还有陈城。
I've seen it.
我已经看到了它。
Thanks to your wife, she alerted me.
感谢你的妻子，她提醒了我。
You didn't forget the task
你没有忘记任务
I gave you, right?
我给你了，对吗？
I wouldn't dare to forget it.
我不敢忘记它。
I've been following Dazhao
我一直在关注大钊
any findings?
有什么发现吗？
Tai Scoop has been acting abnormal recently.
太勺最近表现有些反常。
He seems to be secretly contacting someone.
他似乎在偷偷地联系某人。
But he was afraid to expose his whereabouts.
但他又不敢暴露自己的行踪。
He changes a different phone booth
他换了一个不同的电话亭
every time he calls.
每次他打电话的时候。
That's it?
就是这样？
I haven't finished.
我还没说完呢
Big Scoop knows me.
大勺认识我。
I didn't dare to get too close to him.
我不敢离他太近。
Later on,
稍后的，
I paid off a beggar.
我付钱给了一个乞丐。
To approach him when he made the call.
当他打电话时接近他。
According to the beggar,
据乞丐说，
he was negotiating with the man on the phone about a price.
他正在与电话中的男子谈判价格。
He said he wanted 500 little yellow croakers
他说他想要500条小黄鱼
no one is missing.
没有人失踪。
Five hundred little yellow fishes?
五百条小黄鱼？
That means 30 jin of gold!
那就是30斤黄金啊！
That's right.
这是正确的。
I didn't know these treasures
我不知道这些宝藏
could be sold for so much.
可以卖这么多钱。
Who's on the end of the phone?
电话那头是谁？
Do you know
你知道吗
I don't know.
我不知道。
That's it?
就是这样？
She even went to the camera shop.
她甚至去了相机店。
What?
什么？
He bought a developing tank and fixing powder.
他买了显影槽和定影粉。
Are you going to develop photos?
您要冲洗照片吗？
Exactly.
确切地。
He even put the developed photos in an envelope
他甚至把冲出来的照片装进信封里
the photos in an envelope.
信封里的照片。
Who was it addressed to?
是写给谁的？
That's right.
这是正确的。
I remade the envelope.
我重新制作了信封。
Look at this.
看这个。
That's great.
那太棒了。
How did you get this letter?
你是怎么收到这封信的？
That day, I followed Dashao
那天我跟着大少
I saw him putting a letter in the mailbox
我看见他把一封信放进邮箱
In An De Road.
在安德路。
It was 8 in the morning
当时是早上8点
I know the postman
我认识邮递员
to pick up the mail at 9: 00 a.m.
上午 9: 00 领取邮件
I used the one hour between that
我用了这之间的一小时
of the mailbox with this one hour
这一小时的邮箱
and found the letter in no time
很快就找到了这封信
oh yeah
哦耶
besides the envelope, I also recreated the photo.
除了信封之外，我还重新制作了照片。
I mean, where are you?
我的意思是，你在哪里？
You can't just take them out all at once.
你不能一下子把它们全部拿出来。
I don't want to give you
我不想给你
so frightened, right?
很害怕吧？
Well,
出色地，
both surprise and joy.
既惊喜又喜悦。
What deal?
什么交易？
I'll tell you when.
我会告诉你什么时候。
But you have to remember
但你必须记住
what I told you in the car.
我在车里告诉你的
The Japanese are unreliable now.
日本人现在已经不靠谱了。
We have to think about our own future.
我们必须考虑我们自己的未来。
Alright.
好吧。
When you opened the envelope,
当你打开信封时，
when you opened the envelope, right?
当你打开信封的时候，对吗？
No, it's not.
不，这不对。
On the seal,
印章上，
was opened after being exposed to steam.
暴露于蒸汽后打开。
So it left no trace behind
所以没有留下任何痕迹
chief Chen
陈科长
I decided to be a good person
我决定做一个好人
I'm still not used to it.
我还是不太习惯。
I don't have much experience.
我没有太多经验。
I need your advice.
我需要你的建议。
The second one.
第二个。
The way you pretended to me
你对我假装的样子
with your two pedicure blades.
用你的两个修脚刀片。
How he performed in front of me.
他在我面前的表现如何。
I never thought
我从来没想到
and become a good man again?
并再次成为一个好人？
That's right.
这是正确的。
When I first came into the underworld,
当我第一次来到冥界的时候
I always think the world is so dangerous.
我总觉得这个世界很危险。
One must refrain from evil deeds
人必须戒除恶行
only by doing the most evil.
只有做最邪恶的事。
But now she's a good person.
但现在她是个好人了。
Come in.
进来。
Officer Uchida.
内田警官。
You are Qian Chengyi's
You are Qian Chengyi's
yes
是的
but everyone calls me Qian Xiucai.
但大家都叫我钱秀才。
You wrote the exposure letter?
曝光信是你写的吗？
Saying that Zhao An was actually killed by Luo Guanqun.
话说赵安其实是被罗冠群杀的。
Yes
是的
although there is no direct evidence,
虽然没有直接证据，
but I think it's a reasonable inference.
但我认为这是一个合理的推论。
How long have you been in the reception office?
您在接待处呆了多久了？
More than two years.
两年多了。
What exactly are you going to do?
你到底要做什么？
Receiving and distributing newspapers and letters.
接收和分发报纸和信件。
Look at this.
看这个。
Tell me if you remember anything.
如果你还记得什么，请告诉我。
Check the postmark.
检查邮戳。
The sender's address should be around An De Road.
寄件人地址应在安德路附近。
It could be anyone.
可以是任何人。
To post a letter around An De Road.
去安德路附近寄信。
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
You're right.
你说得对。
Officer.
官。
Can I turn on the lamp?
我可以打开灯吗？
On
在
this letter...
这封信...
Is probably
可能是
from our firm.
来自我们公司。
And mailed them.
并邮寄了它们。
Why did you say that?
你为什么这样说？
The envelope is made of cowhide paper.
信封由牛皮纸制成。
The paper won't seep easily
纸不会轻易渗透
good tenacity
韧性好
It is the first choice for making the envelope.
是制作信封的首选。
But there is a shortage of supplies these years.
但这些年供应短缺。
Now the available envelopes
现在可用的信封
have been replaced by cheap kraft paper.
已被廉价的牛皮纸取代。
Those who continue to use cored paper envelopes
继续使用有芯纸信封的人
are the departments and agencies
是部门和机构
that are working for the new government.
他们正在为新政府工作。
It is said that this kind of paper
据说这种纸
will not see through light.
不会透过光看到。
And it is a strong secret
这是一个强大的秘密
as for An De Road,
至于安德路，
that work for the new government
为新政府工作
only Taihe Business Firm
唯泰和商行
It seems I got the right person.
看来我找对人了。
Please check the envelope.
请检查信封。
Sir,
先生，
this is confidential.
这是保密的。
It's inappropriate with my position.
这与我的立场不合适。
I think it's suitable.
我认为是合适的。
Yes
是的
this movie is very boring,
这部电影很无聊
I suggest you not watch it.
我建议你不要看。
I'm going to marry Yamashita Takeru.
我要嫁给山下健。
Do you look down on me?
你看不起我吗？
I wanted to escape.
我想逃跑。
And I wanted to die.
我想死。
But then I decided to stay.
但后来我决定留下来。
Jiang Zhaoguo wanted me to stay here.
蒋兆国要我留在这里。
But in the end, I've made this choice
但最终我还是做出了这个选择
just for him.
只为他。
Then for what?
那又为了什么？
I don't know either
我也不知道
I have sacrificed everything for him.
我为他牺牲了一切。
My body
我的身体
and my soul.
和我的灵魂。
And my dignity.
还有我的尊严。
I did everything
我做了一切
but I felt that I was wrong
但我觉得我错了
totally wrong.
完全错误的。
Can I do something about it?
我可以做点什么吗？
What?
什么？
I know I don't know you well.
我知道我不太了解你。
But my intuition tells me that
但我的直觉告诉我
you are not like them.
你不像他们。
I won't inquire about your identity.
我不会打听你的身份。
I just wanted to believe you.
我只是想相信你。
So I think
所以我认为
If you can let me do something.
如果你能让我做点什么的话。
For a worthy reason,
出于一个值得的理由，
a noble faith.
崇高的信仰。
In order to make my life
为了让我的生活
to regain value,
重新获得价值，
then...
然后...
What do you want to do?
你想让我做什么？
Right now,
现在，
who can get close to the warrior.
谁能接近武者。
He never told me his secrets.
他从来没有告诉过我他的秘密。
But I know he is very powerful
但我知道他很强大
and is planning something evil.
并正在策划一些邪恶的事情。
Aren't you afraid of danger?
你不怕危险吗？
Not really.
并不真地。
Don't you fear that
你不怕吗
you'll lose the reputation
你会失去声誉
or status,
或状态，
a halo?
你好？
Don't be.
别这样。
I'm not afraid of death.
我不怕死。
But I'm afraid of dying meaninglessly.
但我害怕毫无意义地死去。
Why are you back so late?
你怎么回来这么晚？
Your superior replied to you.
你的上级回复了你。
The application
应用程序
I've submitted it to your organization.
我已将其提交给您的组织。
I can join your organization now.
我现在可以加入你们的组织了。
Don't be anxious.
别着急。
Get me a glass of water.
给我一杯水。
The superior
上级
asked me to investigate you
让我调查你
Investigate you for a while.
调查你一段时间。
You didn't get approved.
你没有得到批准。
Inspection doesn't mean you haven't approved.
检查并不代表你没有批准。
This is a serious and serious matter.
这是一件严肃而严肃的事情。
It's not all about your own will.
这并不完全取决于你自己的意愿。
However,
然而，
the organization has agreed
该组织已同意
to assist me with work.
协助我工作。
So I can help you.
所以我可以帮助你。
To support you?
来支持你？
Luo Guanqun asked me
Luo Guanqun asked me
he asked me to see him tomorrow morning.
他让我明天早上去见他。
There must be something very important.
一定有什么非常重要的事情。
He asked you to rest for a while.
他让你休息一会儿。
That means he needs me to the time.
这意味着他当时需要我。
I'm thinking
我在想
that he has got
他有
the formula in Magpie's hands?
喜鹊手中的配方？
I didn't expect that
我没想到
jun Tong had a fight
佟俊打架了
for the magpie for a while.
为喜鹊暂时。
Finally, they got caught behind.
最后，他们被追在了后面。
Luckily,
幸运的是，
luo Guanqun is just trying to get some leverage.
罗冠群只是想获得一些筹码。
In this way, we'll get our chance.
这样，我们就会得到机会。
What is your plan?
你的计划是什么？
Let me check first.
让我先检查一下。
How Luo Guanqun dealt with Yamashita, right?
罗冠群是怎么对付山下的吧？
And then choose the right opportunity.
然后选择合适的机会。
I want to take part in the operation.
我想参加手术。
According to your organization,
根据您的组织，
I can help you.
我可以帮你。
Alright.
好吧。
You finish reading those books first.
你先把那些书读完。
Why do you read these?
你为什么读这些？
Actually, I was thinking that
其实我是这么想的
If Luo Guanqun might think this simple.
如果罗冠群想得这么简单的话。
He wrote an anonymous letter
他写了一封匿名信
and made an anonymous phone call.
并拨打了匿名电话。
And even bargain with her.
甚至还和她讨价还价。
I don't believe that there is no strategy
我不相信没有策略
you are worried about exposing it.
你担心暴露它。
If it is exposed,
如果暴露的话
luo Guanqun and I will be screwed.
我和罗冠群就完蛋了。
But I still can't understand
但我还是无法理解
what it has to do with reading these books.
这与阅读这些书有什么关系。
Tomorrow afternoon,
明天下午，
tomorrow afternoon
明天下午
to buy clothes for the wedding.
为婚礼买衣服。
You'll go with Han Lu.
你和韩露一起去吧。
Found a place.
找到了一个地方。
In the Gu House.
顾府内。
A three-story Shikumen house.
一栋三层石库门房屋。
It's secluded.
这里很僻静。
The line of sight is fine.
视线没问题。
Which is very convenient for us to monitor.
这对于我们监控来说是非常方便的。
One more thing.
还有一件事。
I also connected a phone line
我还连接了电话线
to get there directly.
直接到达那里。
The phone company.
电话公司。
We'll never find that location.
我们永远找不到那个位置。
Take me there directly.
直接带我去那里。
All right.
好的。
Manager Luo didn't come?
洛经理没来？
It's none of your business.
这不关你的事。
Yes, that's right.
恩，那就对了。
It's Mr. Luo's paper?
这是罗先生的论文？
Section Chief Chen
陈科长
are you here for work?
你来这里是为了工作吗？
Right.
正确的。
So many things happened in the firm recently.
最近公司里发生了很多事情。
I'm so glad to have you back.
我很高兴你回来了。
Right.
正确的。
We have fewer and fewer
我们的数量越来越少
In our business.
在我们的业务中。
That's right
这是正确的
chief Chen
陈科长
I've heard what happened to you
我听说过你发生了什么事
It's really remarkable that
确实很了不起
you're really amazing.
你真是太棒了。
Why didn't you read your Chronicles of the States of Eastern Zhou?
你为什么不读你的《东周国记》？
I've finished.
我做完了。
Finished.
完成的。
I thought you would watch it over and over again.
我以为你会一遍又一遍地观看它。
You don't need to read it over and over again
你不需要一遍又一遍地阅读它
you don't have to read it over and over again?
你不必一遍又一遍地阅读它吗？
Chief Chen
陈科长
he's here
他在这儿
where is Luo?
罗在哪里？
He's waiting for you.
他在等你。
Where is he?
他在哪里？
He's not here.
他不在这儿。
Let me take you there.
让我带你去那里。
Alright.
好吧。
Drive the car.
开车。
No, I won't.
不，我不会。
Don't drive.
不要开车。
Manager Luo said that
罗经理表示
driving in and out.
开车进出。
Caught too much attention.
引起了太多关注。
Let's walk there.
我们去那儿走走吧。
Alright.
好吧。
Who will that be?
那会是谁呢？
This place.
这个地方。
Why did Luo meet me here?
洛怎么会在这里遇见我？
We'll find out after we enter.
我们进去后就知道了。
Is he in the room?
他在房间里吗？
Yes, he's waiting for you.
是的，他在等你。
Brother,
兄弟，
what a shabby place this is!
这是一个多么破旧的地方啊！
This is my command center.
这是我的指挥中心。
Knock it off.
把它关掉。
You don't have to command so shabby.
你没必要指挥得那么破烂。
Someone offered me a lot of money
有人给了我很多钱
to buy the thing I have
买我拥有的东西
what's that
那是什么
the formula of coin paper
硬币纸的配方
I heard about it.
我听说过。
Why do you have it?
为什么你有它？
We are the only ones
我们是唯一的
only you and I,
只有你和我，
big spoon.
大勺子。
The three of us know it.
我们三个人都知道。
If the deal goes down,
如果交易失败
our heads
我们的头脑
land on the ground together.
一起降落在地面上。
Brother,
兄弟，
we've done so much business.
我们已经做了很多生意。
Why do we have to be killed this time?
为什么这次我们一定要被杀？
Do you know who you made deals with this time?
你知道这次你和谁做了交易吗？
Who?
WHO？
Martial arts master under the mountain.
山下武林高手。
Martial Master of the Mountain.
山武师。
Scared?
害怕的？
Chief Chen
陈科长
you can't leave?
你不能离开吗？
You've already known too much.
你已经知道太多了。
Come here.
过来。
Have a seat
请坐
chief Chen
陈科长
have a seat
有座位
and let Manager Luo finish.
让洛经理说完。
Well, brother.
好吧，兄弟。
I'm just a pawn on the stage.
我只是舞台上的一颗棋子。
I can't sing in this play.
这部戏我不会唱歌。
Stop that
不要那么做
you managed to escape from the detention center of the Military Police Headquarters.
你成功逃离了宪兵总部的看守所。
You should do this.
你应该做这个。
Ten big yellow croaker,
大黄鱼十条，
ten fishes?
十条鱼？
Or yellow croaker?
还是黄鱼？
I can't do that either.
我也做不到。
My life is ruined.
我的生活被毁了。
What's the use of money?
钱有什么用？
You know what?
你知道吗？
As long as you use your wits,
只要你发挥你的智慧，
you'll be able to do it.
你一定能做到的。
Then brother,
那么兄弟，
what do you want me to do?
你想要我做什么？
You know
你知道
about the current situation?
关于目前的情况？
In the future,
将来，
more and more miserable.
越来越惨。
You don't want to
你不想
end up in a corner?
最终陷入角落？
I don't want to.
我不想。
The Japanese are not reliable anymore.
日本人已经不靠谱了。
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
Can I rely on money?
我可以依靠金钱吗？
Money every day.
每天都有钱。
Soon the money will become a pile of waste paper.
很快这些钱就会变成一堆废纸。
Gold
金子
you can only count on holding gold.
你只能指望持有黄金。
Aren't you afraid of the Japanese collapsing?
就不怕日本人垮台吗？
Aren't you scared?
你不害怕吗？
The Communists are back against us. Are you scared?
共产党人又回来反对我们了。你怕了吗？
Aren't you scared that the National Army is back?
国军回来你不怕吗？
Or not?
或不？
Let the moon shine on the lakes.
让月光洒满湖面。
Don't be afraid that you can catch the golden hook anywhere.
不要害怕你可以在任何地方抓住金钩。
Enough!
足够的！
Brother. Brother. Brother. Brother.
兄弟。兄弟。兄弟。兄弟。
Stop reciting your stupid poem.
别再背诵你那愚蠢的诗了。
What the hell do you want me to do?
你到底想让我做什么？
My good friend.
我的好朋友。
These words
这些字
are from "Liang You."
出自《梁游》。
Then this person
那么这个人
he will be one of those who subscribed to Good Friend.
他将成为订阅《好朋友》的人之一。
How is the investigation going?
调查进展如何？
No news yet.
还没有消息。
What's the name of the person
这个人叫什么名字
you mentioned before?
你之前提到过？
Is Qian Chengyi
Is Qian Chengyi
are you sure that
你确定吗
he'll be able to find out the truth?
他就能查出真相吗？
If he is in Taihe Trading Firm,
如果他在太和商行的话，
he knows that everyone there
他知道那里的每个人
you have to believe that some people will stop at nothing
你要相信有些人会不择手段
to go upwards.
向上走。
I'm going to prepare the kimono
我去准备和服
to prepare the kimono for the wedding.
准备婚礼的和服。
Once we have something,
一旦我们拥有某样东西，
call Juchuan Riqiao Shop immediately.
立即致电巨川日侨店。
Yes
是的
mr Yamashita
山下先生
has brought Miss Han Lu here.
把韩璐小姐带到了这里。
She's waiting for you outside.
她在外面等你。
I shouldn't have let such a beautiful lady
我不该让这么漂亮的女人
I should have done it.
我应该这么做的。
Mr. Yamashita,
山下先生，
what's the matter?
怎么了？
That man called again.
那个人又打来电话了。
He wants to make a deal today.
他今天想达成协议。
Time and place
时间和地点
how to conduct the transaction?
如何进行交易？
There is a public phone booth beside Pacific Music Store
太平洋琴行旁设有公用电话亭
near Pacific Music Store on Waima Road
外马路太平洋音乐店附近
he asked you to go there alone.
他让你一个人去那里。
Wait for him to call you there at 3 p.m.
等他下午三点打电话给你
You are going alone.
你一个人去。
That's too dangerous.
那太危险了。
He also said
他还说
he will be watching nearby.
他会在附近观看。
Once you find someone is with you,
一旦你发现有人陪着你，
cancel the deal.
取消交易。
I will arrange good people in advance
我会提前安排好的人
around the phone booth
电话亭周围
tell them to never hide
告诉他们永远不要隐藏
and don't be discovered.
并且不要被发现。
Yes
是的
however,
然而，
according to my judgment,
根据我的判断，
the real exchange place
真正的交换场所
wasn't that phone booth
那不是电话亭吗
he still changes his address.
他仍然改变了他的地址。
I'll pretend to follow him
我会假装跟着他
to protect you.
为了保护你。
Catch the blackmailer at the same time.
同时抓住勒索者。
Remember that
请记住
the formula is the most important,
公式最重要，
the most important part is catching him.
最重要的部分是抓住他。
Yes
是的
put the gold in the car.
把金子放进车里。
what about
关于什么
my beautiful Miss Han Lu.
我美丽的韩露小姐。
Have you found your favorite style?
你找到你最喜欢的风格了吗？
Your eyes are blind.
你的眼睛瞎了。
I must go to the store
我必须去商店
and try it on in person.
并亲自试穿。
I'm very sorry.
我很抱歉。
Something came up.
有事发生了。
I won't accompany you now.
我现在不陪你了
But don't worry.
但不用担心。
As soon as I'm done,
我一做完，
I'll come and keep you company.
我会来陪你的。
Alright.
好吧。
Luckily, I have an appointment with Zuo Shuangtao.
幸好我和左双涛有个约会。
I won't be alone anymore.
我不会再孤单了。
Left Shuangtao.
Left Shuangtao.
From Taihe Trading Firm?
泰和商行的？
Right.
正确的。
Her husband Chen Jiaping is my good friend.
她的丈夫陈家平是我的好朋友。
She knows Japanese kimono culture very well.
她非常了解日本的和服文化。
She can give me advice.
她可以给我建议。
That you are willing to wear a kimono
你愿意穿和服
I'm really
我真的
I'm very pleased.
我很高兴。
There're too many people.
人太多了。
We can't investigate one by one
我们无法一一调查
mr. Yamashita,
山下先生，
the outer road is ahead.
外面的路就在前面。
Hello?
你好？
This is Underhill.
这是昂德希尔。
Five minutes from now,
五分钟后，
there is a phone booth
有一个电话亭
telephone booth.
电话亭。
If you are late,
如果你迟到了，
the deal is off.
交易结束了。